Guide to the English Nationality Room Committee Collection, 1931-1981 UA.40.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
English Nationality Room Committee Collection
1931-1981
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Nationality Rooms Program. English Nationality Room Committee
UA.40.07
1.25 Linear Feet 4 boxes
The idea for an English Nationality Room was initially proposed by Dr. Albert Mansbridge in 1927; however, the construction of the room was delayed by the outbreak of the Second World War. Led by Member of Parliament Alfred C. Bossom, the room was eventually constructed using salvaged materials from the bombed House of Commons. This collection contains correspondence, running memos, and photographs that document the construction of the English Nationality Room in the Cathedral of Learning and its dedication in 1952.
Arrangement
The records in this collection were bound into five volumes, each of which are represented as a series in the collection as follows:
Series I. Volume I: History, Minutes, Dr. Mansbridge Correspondence and General Correspondence, 1927-1959
Series II. Volume II: Bossom Correspondence, 1948-1963
Series III. Volume III: Dedication 1952, Gifts 1948-1963, Clippings 1930-1961
Series IV. Volume IV: Architectural Design 1929-1956, Window Rondelles 1952-1958, Furniture 1954-1959
Series V. Volume V: Photographs: Classroom, Dedication, Special Events, Gifts
Biography/History
In 1927, Dr. Albert Mansbridge proposed that an English Room be included in the plan to build Nationality Rooms around the Cathedral of Learning Commons Room. He arranged for the Courtauld Institute of Art in London to hold a competition for English architects to submit either a Georgian or Tudor design for the room. The University of London's architecture professor, Walter Godfrey, won the competition with his Tudor design.
With the outbreak of World War II in 1939 the plans for the English Room were put on hold, but the relationship between England and the United States grew stronger. At the conclusion of the war Alfred C. Bossom, a Member of Parliament, succeeded Dr. Mansbridge as the chairman of the London committee. Bossom identified Victorian era pseudo-Gothic linenfold paneling, stone bosses and a stone fireplace within the bombed House of Commons and secured permission from the Speaker of the House, D. Clifton Brown, to salvage the relics and ship them to Pittsburgh for the English Room. Two rondells are also made of glass taken from the blitzed House of Commons. With the acquisition of these materials and the realization that Andrew W. Mellon served as Ambassador to England, Chancellor Rufus H. Fitzgerald was able to secure a $50,000 grant from the A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust to complete the English Room.
In August 1952 an effort was made to create an English Room committee comprised of Englishmen in the Pittsburgh community to complete the room's construction, such as the installation of twenty-two stained glass medallions containing the coats of arms of English universities and cities. L. Gerald First was named the first chair of this committee and on November 21, 1952, the English Room was dedicated.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists primarily of correspondence documenting the English Nationality Room Committee's efforts to secure funding, an architectural design and items for the room. Of particular interest is the correspondence of Alfred Bossom, who was the committee chair in England that arranged for the support of the British government. Also included are committee meeting minutes and running memos, which document the progress being made during the room's construction. Information regarding the room's 1952 dedication and photographs are also present.
Acquisition Information
Transferred to the University Archives by the Nationality Rooms Program Office in 1999.
Previous Citation
English Nationality Room Committee Collection, 1931-1981, UA.40.07, University of Pittsburgh Archives
Clippings (Information artifacts); University of Pittsburgh; Classrooms -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Photographs; Minutes (Administrative records); Financial records; Correspondence; Nationality Rooms (Cathedral of Learning, Pittsburgh, Pa.); Godfrey, Walter H.; Mitchell, Ruth Crawford; Mansbridge, Albert; Bossom, Alfred C.; University of Pittsburgh. Nationality Rooms Program; University of Pittsburgh. Nationality Rooms Program. English Nationality Room Committee
- Volume I: History, Minutes, Dr. Mansbridge Correspondence and General Correspondence, 1927-1959; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This volume contains a variety of documents relating to the creation and maintenance of the English Nationality Room. Included are correspondence with the first committee chair, Albert Mansbridge, discussing pre-World WAr Ii efforts to build an English Room and running memos which document the room's construction. Also present are correspondence and committee meeting minutes which document the maintenance and evolution of the room after its dedication in 1952, as well as histories of the room written by Ruth Crawford Mitchell.
  - History of the English Room, 1.
    - History of the Room, 1927-1952, by Ruth Crawford Mitchell (Volume 1, Item 1)
    - Revised History of the English Room by Ruth Crawford Mitchell, c. 1956 (Item 2)
    - Description and History of the Room by Ruth Crawford Mitchell, 1951 (Item 3)
  - Running Memos, 1931-1958; 2.
    - Running Memo, 1931 (Item 1)
    - Running Memo, 1932 (Item 2)
    - Running Memo, 1933 (Item 3)
    - Running Memo, 1934 (Item 4)
    - Running Memo, 1935 (Item 5)
    - Running Memo, 1936 (Item 6)
    - Running Memo, 1937 (Item 7)
    - Running Memo, 1938 (Item 8)
    - Running Memo, 1939 (Item 9)
    - Running Memo, 1940 (Item 10)
    - Running Memo, 1941 (Item 11)
    - Running Memo, 1942 (Item 12)
    - Running Memo, 1943 (Item 13)
    - Running Memo, 1944-1946 (Item 14)
    - Running Memo, 1947 (Item 15)
    - Running Memo, 1948 (Item 16)
      - Meeting of English Steering Committee, December 20, 1948; 1.
    - Running Memo, 1953 (Item 17)
    - Running Memo, 1954 (Item 18)
    - Running Memo, 1956 (Item 19)
    - Running Memo, 1957 (Item 20)
      - Mitchell to Rupp, January 18, 1957; 1.
      - Appeal Letter by R. Hadden, February 11, 1957; 2.
      - Memo from Mitchell to Elliott, July 23, 1957; 3.
      - English Room Statement No. 1, December 12, 1952; 4.
      - English Room Statement No. 2, 5.
      - English Room Statement No. 3, 6.
      - English Room Statement No. 4, 7.
    - Running Memo, 1958 (Item 21)
    - Running Memo, 1959 (Item 22)
  - Minutes of the English Room Committee, 1952-1958; 3.
    - Committee Minutes, 1952 (Item 1)
      - Minutes, September 26, 1952; 1.
      - Report of the Chairman, October 8, 1952; 2.
      - Firth to English Room Committees, October 7, 1952; 3.
      - Minutes, October 10, 1952; 4.
      - Minutes, October 17, 1952; 5.
      - Minutes, October 24, 1952; 6.
      - Minutes, November 7, 1952; 7.
    - Committee Minutes, 1953 (Item 2)
      - Minutes, January 27, 1953; 1.
      - Minutes, May 22, 1952; 2.
      - Firth to English Room Committees, May 27, 1953; 3.
      - Minutes, June 16, 1953; 4.
      - Minutes, September 14, 1953; 5.
      - Financial Statement, September 14, 1953; 6.
      - Minutes, December 15, 1953; 7.
      - Memorandum on Conferences, September 22, 1953; 8.
    - Committee Minutes, 1954 (Item 3)
      - Minutes, March 16, 1954; 1.
      - Minutes, October 21, 1954; 2.
      - Sub-Committee Meeting Minutes, November 15, 1954; 3.
    - Committee Minutes, 1955 (Item 4)
      - Minutes, January 11, 1955; 1.
      - Minutes, March 3, 1955; 2.
    - Committee Minutes, 1956 (Item 5)
      - Minutes, January 3, 1956; 1.
      - Memo from Firth to English Room Committee, December 10, 1956; 2.
      - Minutes, December 17, 1956; 3.
    - Committee Minutes, 1957 (Item 6)
    - Committee Minutes, 1958 (Item 7)
      - Minutes, January 6, 1958; 1.
      - Minutes, July 7, 1958; 2.
      - Perry to Mitchell, July 7, 1958; 3.
      - Meeting Minutes Corrections, July 7, 1958; 4.
      - Minutes (Corrected), July 7, 1958; 5.
      - List of Committee Members, July 7, 1958; 6.
      - Agenda, September 13, 1958; 7.
      - Memo from Mitchell to English Folder, September 15, 1958; 8.
      - Financial Report, September 13, 1958; 9.
      - Handwritten Meeting Minutes, September 13, 1958; 10.
  - Correspondence, Dr. Albert Mansbridge, 1934-1947; 4.
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Item 1)
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, April 21, 1934; 1.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, April 21, 1934; 2.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, June 19, 1934; 3.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, June 22, 1934; 4.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, July 17, 1934; 5.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, August 16, 1934; 6.
      - Edwards to Mitchell, September 3, 1934; 7.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, October 10, 1934; 8.
      - Constable to Mitchell, October 15, 1934; 9.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, October 18, 1934; 10.
      - Mitchell to Constable, November 28, 1934; 11.
      - Constable to Mitchell, December 11, 1934; 12.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, December 12, 1934; 13.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, December 27, 1934; 14.
    - Correspondence, 1935 (Item 2)
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, January 8, 1935; 1.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, January 17, 1935; 2.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, February 5, 1935; 3.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, February 10, 1935; 4.
      - Mansbridge to Smalley, February 10, 1935; 5.
      - Mansbridge to Professor Tyson, July 11, 1935; 6.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, October 28, 1935; 7.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, October November 11, 1935; 8.
      - Constable to Mansbridge, December 12, 1935; 9.
      - Mansbridge to Bowman, December 15, 1935; 10.
      - Mitchell to Constable, December 17, 1935; 11.
    - Correspondence, 1936 (Item 3)
      - Constable to Mitchell, January 3, 1936; 1.
      - Mitchell to Constable, January 17, 1936; 2.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, January 27, 1936; 3.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, February 5, 1936; 4.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, February, 19, 1936; 5.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, April 13, 1936; 6.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, April 23, 1936; 7.
      - Constable to Mansbridge, April 23, 1936; 8.
      - Mansbridge to Bowman, May 21, 1936; 9.
      - Constable to Bowman, May 22, 1936; 10.
      - Bowman to Constable, July 7, 1936; 11.
      - Bowman to Mansbridge, July 7, 1936; 12.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, July 8, 1936; 13.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, July 21, 1936; 14.
      - Constable to Bowman, July 23, 1936; 15.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, July 31, 1936; 16.
      - Stegeman to Constable, August 12, 1936; 17.
      - Bowman to Mansbridge, August 12, 1936; 18.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, August 18, 1936; 19.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, August 18, 1936; 20.
      - Constable to Mitchell, October 1, 1936; 21.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, October 8, 1936; 22.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, October 20, 1936; 23.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, December 4, 1936; 24.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, December 9, 1936; 25.
    - Correspondence, 1937 (Item 4)
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, March 8, 1937; 1.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, March 18, 1937; 2.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, July 2, 1937; 3.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, July 13, 1937; 4.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, July 21, 1937; 5.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, 6.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, October 20, 1937; 7.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, November 13, 1937; 8.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, November 24, 1937; 9.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, December 7, 1937; 10.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, December 19, 1937; 11.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, December 30, 1937; 12.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, December 30, 1937; 13.
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Item 5)
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, January 10, 1938; 1.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, January 18, 1938; 2.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, January 28, 1938; 3.
      - Godfrey to Mitchell, February 4, 1938; 4.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, February 7, 1938; 5.
      - Mansbridge to Godfrey, February 8, 1938; 6.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, February 8, 1938; 7.
      - Hickson to Mitchell, February 12, 1938; 8.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, February 17, 1938; 9.
      - Hickson to Mitchell, February 22, 1938; 10.
      - Hickson to Mitchell, March 21, 1938; 11.
      - Hickson to Mitchell, March 24, 1938; 12.
      - Mitchell to Hickson, March 24, 1938; 13.
      - Summary of Conferences with Hickson, Mitchell, and Bowman, March 31 and April1, 1938; 14.
      - Summary of Discussions with Mrs. Mitchell and Dr. Bowman, March 31 and April 1, 1938; 15.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, April 1, 1938; 16.
      - Mitchell to Mansbridge, April 4, 1938; 17.
      - Mansbridge to Mitchell, April 18, 1938; 18.
      - Mitchell to Godfrey, April 21, 1938; 19.
      - Hickson to Mitchell, May 7, 1938; 20.
      - Mitchell to Hickson, May 9, 1938; 21.
      - Walter Godfrey to Mitchell, May 9, 1938; 22.
      - Hickson to Mitchell, May 17, 1938; 23.
      - Bowman to Guinness, May 20, 1938; 24.
      - Bowman to Bolton, May 20, 1938; 25.
      - Mansbridge to Bowman, June 3, 1938; 26.
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Item 6)
      - Mansfield to Mitchell, June 20, 1939; 1.
      - Mitchell to Mansfield, August 4, 1939; 2.
      - Mitchell to Harnies, July 29, 1939; 3.
      - Harnies to Mitchell, August 3, 1939; 4.
      - Mansfield to Mitchell, August 3, 1939; 5.
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Item 7)
      - Bentley to Bowman, October 26, 1942; 1.
      - Memorandum by F.H. Bentley, February 10, 1942; 2.
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Item 8)
      - Bentley to Fitzgerald, February 25, 1946; 1.
      - Fitzgerald to Bentley, March 21, 1946; 2.
      - Bentley to Mitchell, April 18, 1946; 3.
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Item 9)
      - Bentley to Tyson, April 8, 1947; 1.
  - General Correspondence, 1948-1963; 5.
    - General Correspondence, 1948 (Item 1)
      - Presentation of the Nationality Rooms book to the British Ambassador, January 28, 1948; 1.
      - Inverchapel to Fitzgerald, January 30, 1948; 2.
      - Mitchell to Bell, April 21, 1948; 3.
      - Bell to Mitchell, May 17, 1948; 4.
      - Mitchell to Bell, May 18, 1948; 5.
    - General Correspondence, 1949 (Item 2)
      - Mitchell to Walton, March 8, 1949; 1.
      - Clifton Brown to Fitzgerald, November 15, 1949; 2.
      - Fitzgerald to Clifton Brown, December 23, 1949; 3.
    - General Correspondence, 1950 (Item 3)
      - Mitchell to Charles, January 27, 1950; 1.
      - R.L. Swearer to Mitchell, March 3, 1950; 2.
      - Dotter to Twigger, March 8, 1950; 3.
      - Invoice, 4.
      - Invoice of Merchandise, January 26, 1950; 5.
      - Weber to Collector of Customs, March 8, 1950; 6.
      - R.L. Swearer to Dotter, March 9, 1950; 7.
      - Bossom to Fitzgerald, March 21, 1950; 8.
      - Invoice, March 31, 1950; 9.
      - Franks to Fitzgerald, April7, 1950; 10.
      - Willard to Mitchell, July 8, 1950; 11.
      - Willard to Mitchell, July 11, 1950; 12.
      - Mitchell to Willard, July 14, 1950; 13.
      - Willard to University, July 19, 1950; 14.
      - Willard to Mitchell, July 19, 1950; 15.
      - Twigger to Mitchell, July 26, 1950; 16.
      - Willard to Alfred Bossom, July 26, 1950; 17.
      - Willard to Mitchell, October 6, 1950; 18.
    - General Correspondence, 1951 (Item 4)
      - Hawes to Fitzgerald, April 20, 1951; 1.
      - Fitzgerald to Hawes, May 10, 1951; 2.
      - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, July 6, 1951; 3.
      - Brochure, "Anglo-American Civilization Interdepartmental Major", 4.
      - A.K. Smith to Fitzgerald, July 4, 1951; 5.
      - Fitzgerald to Smith, June 28, 1951; 6.
      - Telegram from Clifton Brown to Fitzgerald, July 7, 1951; 7.
      - Clifton Brown to Fitzgerald, July 6, 1951; 8.
      - Fitzgerald to Clifton Brown, June 28, 1951; 9.
      - Fitzgerald to Bossom, July 7, 1951; 10.
      - Bossom to Fitzgerald, July 3, 1951; 11.
      - Fitzgerald to Bossom, June 28, 1951; 12.
      - Presentation of Nationality Rooms Book to Clifton Brown, July 17, 1951; 13.
      - Detailed Description of the English Room, July 1951; 14.
      - History of the Room, July 1951; 15.
      - Presentation of Nationality Rooms Book (copy), July 17, 1951; 16.
      - Heath to Fitzgerald, July 18, 1951; 17.
      - Mitchell to Fitzgerald, July 20, 1951; 18.
      - Browne to Fitzgerald, July 26, 1951; 19.
      - Bossom to Fitzgerald, July 27, 1951; 20.
    - General Correspondence, 1952 (Item 5)
      - Bishop Brown to McCarthy, November 5, 1952; 1.
    - General Correspondence, 1958 (Item 6)
      - Martin to Rankin, October 2, 1958; 1.
      - Martin to Rankin, November 20, 1958; 2.
      - Memo from Mitchell to Witman, November 21, 1958 (?); 3.
      - Memo from Witman to Rankin, November 24, 1958; 4.
      - Bossom to Mitchell, December 12, 1958; 5.
      - Memo from Witman to Rankin, December 16, 1958; 6.
    - General Correspondence, 1959 (Item 7)
      - Memo from Witman regarding Churchill Portrait, February 9, 1959; 1.
      - Rankin to Martin, February 23, 1959; 2.
      - Mitchell to Witman, June 18, 1959; 3.
      - Mitchell to Witman, June 18, 1959; 4.
      - Leather to Mitchell, June 30, 1959; 5.
    - General Correspondence, 1962 (Item 8)
      - Mitchell to Eldridge, November 14, 1962; 1.
      - Eldridge to Finegold, November 26, 1962; 2.
      - Nationality Rooms Council to Bruce, November 10, 1962; 3.
    - General Correspondence, 1963 (Item 9)
      - Eldridge to Finegold, February 5, 1963; 1.
      - Elkus to Eldridge, March 18, 1963; 2.
      - Finegold to Eldridge, April 3, 1963; 3.
      - Mitchell to Bossom, August 7, 1963; 4.
      - Bossom to Mitchell, August 13, 1963; 5.
  - Associated Papers (In front cover of volume), 6.
    - List of English Room Committees, November 8, 1952 (Item 1)
    - Martin to Dowd Chair Rental & Sales, December 23, 1953 (Item 2)
    - Press Release, April 4, 1974 (Item 3)
    - Notebook Sheet with Handwrtten Notes (Item 4)
- Volume II: Bossom Correspondence, 1948-1963; II.
  Alfred C. Bossom replaced Dr. Albert Mansbridge as chair of the London Committee of the English Room at the conclusion of the Second World War. Before serving as a Member of Parliament, he was an architect in Pittsburgh. Through Bossom's connections to the British government, he was able to secure many of the features of the English Room from the bombed House of Commons and several other artifacts and gifts. This volume of correspondence provides information about his contributions to the room and his pursuit and acquisition of architectual and artifactual items, such as the cast iron fire back depicting the defeat of the Spanish Armada.
  - Correspondence, 1948; 1.
    - Bossom to Burbidge, January 3, 1948 (Volume 2, Item 1)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, February 6, 1948 (Item 2)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, February 16, 1948 (Item 3)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 9, 1948 (Item 4)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 6, 1948 (Item 5)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, March 16, 1948 (Item 6)
    - Agnes L. Starrett to Stanley Morrison, February 12, 1948 (Item 7)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 31, 1948 (Item 8)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, May 18, 1948 (Item 9)
    - Guy Chapman to Bossom (Item 10)
    - Chapman and Mitchell to Bossom, December 13, 1948 (Item 11)
  - Correspondence, 1949; 2.
    - Mitchell to Bossom, March 9, 1949 (Item 1)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 21, 1949 (Item 2)
    - Fitzgerald to Bossom, June 11, 1949 (Item 3)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 22, 1949 (Item 4)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, October 13, 1949 (Item 5)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 20, 1949 (Item 6)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, October 25, 1949 (Item 7)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, November 10, 1949 (Item 8)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, November 30, 1949 (Item 9)
  - Correspondence, 1950; 3.
    - Bossom to Mitchell, January 10, 1950 (Item 1)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, January 20, 1950 (Item 2)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, January 25, 1950 (Item 3)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, April 18, 1950 (Item 4)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April 18, 1950 (Item 5)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, April 19, 1950 (Item 6)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, April 26, 1950 (Item 7)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 5, 1950 (Item 8)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 18, 1950 (Item 9)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 25, 1950 (Item 10)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 31, 1950 (Item 11)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, May 26, 1950 (Item 12)
    - Mansbridge to Fitzgerald, June 13, 1950 (Item 13)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, June 29, 1950 (Item 14)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, August 3, 1950 (Item 15)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, August 15, 1950 (Item 16)
    - List of English Room Details in which assistance is needed from London, August 15, 1950 (Item 17)
    - Memorandum on Design, June 1949 (Item 18)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, August 18, 1950 (Item 19)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 2, 1950 (Item 20)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, October 9, 1950 (Item 21)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 14, 1950 (Item 22)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 17, 1950 (Item 23)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 25, 1950 (Item 24)
    - Bossom to Fitzgerald, November 1, 1950 (Item 25)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, November 16, 1950 (Item 26)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, November 17, 1950 (Item 27)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, November 1950 (Item 28)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 12, 1950 (Item 29)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 29, 1950 (Item 30)
  - Correspondence, 1951; 4.
    - Dotter to Bossom, January 5, 1951 (Item 1)
    - Dotter to Bossom, January 7, 1951 (Item 2)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 15, 1951 (Item 3)
    - Bossom to Dotter, January 18, 1951 (Item 4)
    - Coote to Bossom (Item 5)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, February 20, 1951 (Item 6)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, February 23, 1951 (Item 7)
    - Memorandum, February, 26, 1951 (Item 8)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 27, 1951 (Item 9)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April 2, 1951 (Item 10)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, June 9, 1951 (Item 11)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, June 29, 1951 (Item 12)
    - Memo to Mitchell, June 30, 1951 (Item 13)
    - Memo to Mitchell, July 3, 1951 (Item 14)
    - Memo to Mitchell, July 27, 1951 (Item 15)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Roger Russell, June 20, 1951 (Item 16)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Roger Russell, June 21, 1951 (Item 17)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Bishop Brown, June 25, 1951 (Item 18)
    - Telegram sent to Mitchell (Item 19)
    - Telegram sent to Mitchell, June 22, 1951 (Item 20)
    - Roger Carter to Mitchell, June 21, 1951 (Item 21)
    - Roger Russell to Mitchell, June 22, 1951 (Item 22)
    - A.W. Schmidt to Julius C. Holmes, June 27, 1951 (Item 23)
    - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, July 3, 1951 (Item 24)
    - Mitchell to Roger Russell, July 3, 1951 (Item 25)
    - Clifton Brown to Fitzgerald, July 3, 1951 (Item 26)
    - Bossom to Fitzgerald, July 3, 1951 (Item 27)
    - Roger Carter to Mitchell, July 5, 1951 (Item 28)
    - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, July 6, 1951 (Item 29)
    - Suggested Radio Talk about the University of Pittsburgh - Drafts (Item 30)
    - List of Potential Invitees for Luncheon (Item 31)
    - List of Members of the United States Educational Commission in the United Kingdom (Fullbright) (Item 32)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Richard Taylor, July 7, 1951 (Item 33)
    - Telegram from Fitzgerald to Clifton Brown, July 7, 1951 (Item 34)
    - Telegram from Fitzgerald to Bossom, July 7, 1951 (Item 35)
    - Mitchell to Richard Taylor, July 7, 1951 (Item 36)
    - Richard Taylor to Mitchell, July 10, 1951 (Item 37)